Guide to the Thomas Day Thacher Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Speeches, 1925-1949; Series III; 2.25 linear feet (5 boxes)
  - "Modernizing our Bankruptcy Laws", 1934 November 14 (Box 63, Folder 776)
  - Legal Aid Society, 1934 November 15 (Box 63, Folder 777)
  - "Administrative Tribunals vs. Courts Under the New Deal", 1934 November 24 (Box 63, Folder 778)
  - Fitness of trial lawyers, [?]1935 (Box 63, Folder 779)
  - Induction of Presiding Justice Francis Martin, 1935 January 2 (Box 63, Folder 780)
  - "Invasions of Judicial Powers", 1935 January 25 (Box 63, Folder 781)
  - Colleagues to judge legal competence and character of lawyer, 1935 Feb25 (Box 63, Folder 782)
  - President's address to NYC Bar Association, 1935 May 14 (Box 63, Folder 783)
  - Practice of law, 1935 June 24 (Box 63, Folder 784)
  - "Backgrounds of Recent Legislation for the Relief of Debtors", 1935 December 7 (Box 63, Folder 785)
  - New York City charter revision, 1936 April 29 (Box 63, Folder 786)
  - New York City charter revision: planning, 1936 May 2 (Box 63, Folder 787)
  - "The New City Charter", 1936 May 6 (Box 63, Folder 788)
  - "Charter Revision", 1936 May 7 (Box 63, Folder 789)
  - "Borough Autonomy Under the New Charter", 1936 May 12 (Box 63, Folder 790)
  - The New City Charter, 1936 May 20 (Box 63, Folder 791)
  - "Charter Revision", 1936 May 28 (Box 63, Folder 792)
  - "A New Charter for New York City, 1936 June 9 (Box 63, Folder 793)
  - New York City Charter, 1936 June 24 (Box 63, Folder 794)
  - "New York City's Proposed New Charter", 1936 August 17 (Box 63, Folder 795)
  - "The Proper Conduct of Trials and Publicity in Relation Thereto", 1936 August 25 (Box 63, Folder 796)
  - "The New City Charter", 1936 September 3 (Box 63, Folder 797)
  - Charter Revision, 1936 October 20 (Box 63, Folder 788)
  - "The New City Charter", 1936 October 23 (Box 64, Folder 799)
  - "Spending the City's Money Under the New Charter", 1936 October 29 (Box 64, Folder 800)
  - "The Last Word on the New City Charter - Vote 'YES'", 1936 November 2 (Box 64, Folder 801)
  - Charter Revision Commission's victory dinner, 1936 December 14 (Box 64, Folder 802)
  - "Medicine and the State" - speech and correspondence, 1937 January 7 (Box 64, Folder 803)
  - "Medicine and the State" - research, 1937 January 7 (Box 64, Folder 804)
  - Education at Andover, 1937 March 12 (Box 64, Folder 805)
  - Planning Commission and Council members under new Charter, 1937 July 7 (Box 64, Folder 806)
  - Election of Councilmen in New York City, 1937 October 18 (Box 64, Folder 807)
  - "The Supreme Court and its Relations to the Executive and Legislative Departments of the Government", 1937 November 23 (Box 64, Folder 808)
  - In honor of John W. Davis, 1938 May 5 (Box 64, Folder 809)
  - Alex Gumberg funeral speech, 1939 June 2 (Box 64, Folder 810)
  - Judicial authority and law, 1939 October 24 (Box 64, Folder 811)
  - "Issues of the Council Campaign", 1939 November 1 (Box 64, Folder 812)
  - History of U.S. District Court for the Southern District of New York, 1939 November 3 (Box 64, Folder 813)
  - Administrative offices and law, 1940 January 26 (Box 65, Folder 814)
  - Memorial speech for Pierce Butler, 1940 January 27 (Box 65, Folder 815)
  - "Organization of the Supreme Court", 1940 February 1 (Box 65, Folder 816)
  - 50 anniversary of Taft School - unveiling of bust, 1940 May 25 (Box 65, Folder 817)
  - "The Key to Democracy", 1940 October 15 (Box 65, Folder 818)
  - Wilkie-McNary campaign, 1940 October 28 (Box 65, Folder 819)
  - On FDR's third nomination, 1940 November 1 (Box 65, Folder 820)
  - "Why Five Sheriffs? The Need for County Reform", 1941 May 23 (Box 65, Folder 821)
  - 50th anniversary of Yale Law Journal, 1941 April 19 (Box 65, Folder 822)
  - "Young People in the Courts of New York State", 1942 December 2 (Box 65, Folder 823)
  - Introduction of Lord and Lady Beveridge, 1943 June 3 (Box 65, Folder 824)
  - Armistice Day speech, 1943 November 11 (Box 66, Folder 825)
  - Liberal education, 1944 June 29 (Box 66, Folder 826)
  - Form of briefs, 1946 May 18 (Box 66, Folder 827)
  - Judge B. Learned Hand Memorial to Harvard, 1947 April 2 (Box 66, Folder 828)
  - "The Advocate's Part in the Judicial Process", 1947 May 8 (Box 66, Folder 829)
  - History of the Inns of Court, 1948 January 24 (Box 66, Folder 830)
  - "The Citizen and the New York City Planning Commission: Introductory Remarks", 1948 April 8 (Box 66, Folder 831)
  - Response to Chief Judge Longhran's farewell address on behalf of the Court, 1949 February 23 (Box 66, Folder 832)
  - Notes for speeches, undated (Box 66, Folder 833)
  - Speech at Yale, undated (Box 66, Folder 834)
  - Judiciary reform, undated (Box 66, Folder 835)
  - "The Old Boys of Taft", undated (Box 66, Folder 836)
  - Presentation of Oliver Ellsworth's portrait, undated (Box 66, Folder 837)
  - Lawyer's professional obligations, undated (Box 66, Folder 838)
  - Legal practice in New York City, undated (Box 66, Folder 839)
  - U.S. District Court, undated (Box 66, Folder 840)
  - Material for speeches (Box 66, Folder 841-842)
- Biographical Material and Memorabilia, 1917-1950; Series IV; 3.5 linear feet (8 boxes and one oversize folio)
  General note
  Folio
  The file folders of Series IV are arranged alphabetically. Photographs and appointment books are arranged chronologically.
  - Books: orders and receipts, 1944-1950 (Box 67, Folder 843-844)
  - Campaign contributions, 1937-1939 (Box 67, Folder 845)
  - Caviar: correspondence and memoranda re: orders for gifts, 1934-1935 (Box 67, Folder 846)
  - Christmas gifts and contributions, 1943-1948 (Box 67, Folder 847)
  - Columbia University: contribution to Werner Hegemann's salary, 1935-1937 (Box 67, Folder 848)
  - Court of Appeals: correspondence and memoranda re: Pension Plan, 1944-1948 (Box 67, Folder 849)
  - Court of Appeals: correspondence and memoranda re: Salary, 1943-1948 (Box 67, Folder 850)
  - Descendants of T.D. Thacher (list) (Box 67, Folder 851)
  - Fiduciary Trust Co. of New York: statements, 1944-1945 (Box 67, Folder 852)
  - Fishing information and trips, 1934-1948 (Box 67, Folder 853)
  - Golf: correspondence and information (Box 67, Folder 854)
  - Hillman's Ranch, Wyoming, 1927 (Box 67, Folder 855)
  - Honorary degrees
    - Columbia University - correspondence, 1945 June 5 (Box 67, Folder 856)
    - Harvard University - address and correspondence, 1944 June 29 (Box 67, Folder 857)
    - New York University - correspondence and memoranda, 1944 June 7 (Box 68, Folder 858)
    - University of Wisconsin - correspondence, address clippings on Glenn Frank, President of the university, 1935 June 24 (Box 68, Folder 859)
    - Yale University, 1930 June (Box 68, Folder 860)
  - Loans, bad debts, bad checks: correspondence and memoranda, 1930-1938 (Box 68, Folder 861)
  - Morris and Essex Railroad Company stock (Box 68, Folder 862)
  - New York State Unemployment Fund
    - Quarterly payroll reports and information, 1937 January 1 - 1939 April 1 (Box 68, Folder 863)
    - Quarterly payroll reports, 1939 April 1 - 1943 December 31 (Box 68, Folder 864)
  - Prayer of Henry Sloane Coffin given at T.D. Thacher funeral service, 1950 November 14 (Box 68, Folder 865)
  - Psi Upsilon, 1941 (Box 68, Folder 866)
  - Receipts for personal items: clothing, club bills, etc., 1935-1943 (Box 68, Folder 867-868)
  - Red Cross: correspondence and memoranda, 1917-1918 (Box 68, Folder 869)
  - Scudder, Stevens and Clark (investment counselors): correspondence and memoranda re: stocks, 1931-1943 (Box 69, Folder 870-872)
  - Subscriptions: schools, YMCA, church, etc., 1927-1933 (Box 69, Folder 873)
  - Subscriptions to journals, etc: lists and correspondence, 1935-1943 (Box 69, Folder 874)
  - Taxes
    - Federal and state information returns, 1938-1943 (Box 69, Folder 875)
    - Employee payroll, 1935-1943 (Box 69, Folder 876)
    - Records for Myrtle B. Vaughan, 1936-1943 (Box 69, Folder 877)
    - Victory and witholding, 1942-1943 (Box 69, Folder 878)
  - Travel
    - London - correspondence and memoranda, 1929 (Box 70, Folder 879)
    - London, 1933 (Box 70, Folder 880)
    - London and Ireland, 1938, 1939 (Box 70, Folder 881)
  - United Republican Finance Committee contributions, 1940-1942 (Box 70, Folder 882)
  - U.S. News: correspondence re: support, 1933-1943 (Box 70, Folder 883)
  - Vassar College common stock control plan, 1940 (Box 70, Folder 884)
  - Victory Fund Committee, 1942 (Box 70, Folder 885)
  - Wages: servants', [?] - 1943 (Box 70, Folder 886)
  - Miscellaneous personal information (Box 70, Folder 887)
  - Passports (Box 71, Folder 888-889)
  - Warrant by King Albert of Belgium naming Thacher "Chevalier de la Couponne", 1919 December 22 (Box 71, Folder 890)
  - Eminent Members of the Bench and Bar (photographs), 1916-1917 (Box 71, Folder 891)
  - Personal address book (Box 71, Folder 892)
  - Address book (Box 71, Folder 893)
  - Scrapbook - clippings, 1925-1930 (Box 72, Folder 894)
  - Clippings, 1933-1934 (Box 72, Folder 895-896)
  - Scrapbook - clippings, 1933-1939, 1943-1948 (Box 72, Folder 897-898)
  - Clippings, 1949 (Box 72, Folder 899)
  - Appointment books, 1926-1930, 1932-1935 (Box 73, Folder 900)
  - Appointment books, 1936-1943 (Box 74, Folder 901)
  - Thomas Day Thacher photographs (Box 75)
    Includes photographs of the 35th reunion of the Class of 1904 (1939); Tacher's wife; Thacher with his son and grandson (1949), Thacher as judge; youth; and Hoover Administration playing volleyball.
- Additional material, 1779-1984, undated; Accession 2000-M-103
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Thomas Thacher, 1999.
  The addition is composed of correspondence, files, printed matter, bound volumes, maps, and drawings. The materials were arranged in sections corresponding to the original accession. The addition includes Correspondence, Subject Files, and Thacher Family Materials.
  Conditions Governing Access
  These records are closed, pending review by donor.
  - Correspondence, 1914-1950, undated
    - General correspondence-incoming and outgoing, 1914-1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Reed, Lansing P., 1938-1944, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Subject Files, 1925-1948
    - Solicitor General, 1930-1932
      - U. S. Supreme Court Cases Argued October Term 1930-Vols. 1-2 (Box 2)
      - U. S. Supreme Court Cases Argued October Term 1930-Vol. 7 (Box 3)
      - U. S. Supreme Court Cases Argued October Term 1931-Vols. 3-4 (Box 4)
      - U. S. Supreme Court Cases Argued October Term 1931-Vols. 5-6 (Box 5)
      - U. S. Supreme Court Cases Argued October Term 1932-Vols. 1 and 3 (Box 6)
      - U. S. Supreme Court Cases Argued October Term 1932-Vols. 5 and 7 (Box 7)
    - United States District Court Judge, 1925-1930
      - Memoranda of Cases Decided-Judge Thomas D. Thacher 1927, (Vols. 1, 2), 1928, Vol. 1, 1927, 1928 (Box 8)
      - Opinions-1925 (Vol. 1), 1926, Vol. 2, 1925, 1926 (Box 9)
      - Opinions-1927 (Vol. 3) (Box 10)
      - Opinions-1928 (Vol. 4) (Box 11)
      - Opinions-1929 (Vol. 5) and 1930, 1929, 1930 (Box 12)
    - New York City Politics and Charter Revision, 1935
      - New York City Charter Commission minutes, 1935, undated (Box 13, Folder 1-7)
        - Additional material (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
    - Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1925-1948
      - Capshaw, Hulon-investigation of, 1930-1944, undated (Box 14, Folder 5-8)
        - Additional material (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
      - Charity organizations and information reports, 1934-1935 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Charitable organization donations, 1931-1943, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Importation of glassware, 1926-1930 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Inns of Court, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Ireland travel, 1947-1948, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Kunstler, Harold-investigation of, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Martin, George W.-investigation of, 1938-1939 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - O'Dwyer, William-investigation of, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Thacher Family Materials, 1779-1984
    - Burrall, Estate of Edward M., 1944-1945, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Burrall, Lucy, 1893-1936, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Burrall, Estate of Mary Eunice, 1920-1946, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Genealogy of Thacher-Thatcher
      - Thacher-Thatcher Genealogy, Part I Coat of Arms, Parts I, XIII- XXII., circa 1915 (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
      - A Record of Descendants of Rev. Peter Thacher, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Portrait-Oxenbridge Thacher, 1779-1940, undated (Box 17, Folder 1-4)
    - St. John's Parish, Waterbury, CT, 1925-1948, undated (Box 17, Folder 5-6)
    - Thacher, Eunice Burrall, 1924-1950
      - Correspondence, 1924-1942 (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
      - Thacher, Estate of Eunice Burrall, 1928-1950 (Box 17, Folder 9)
        - Additional material (Box 18, Folder 1-4)
    - The Thacher School, 1939-1949 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Thacher, Thomas Day, 1939-1984
      - Columbia University -oral history relating to American Red Cross mission to Russia, 1949-1979 (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
      - Condolences relating to Eunice Burrall Thacher's death, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Estate of Thomas Day Thacher, 1939-1984
        - Correspondence, 1950-1984 (Box 18, Folder 9-10)
          - Additional material (Box 19, Folder 1-8)
        - Court accountings, 1950-1981 (Box 19, Folder 9)
          - Additional material (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
        - Miscellaneous, 1939-1954 (Box 20, Folder 3)
        - Probate court, 1951-1957 (Box 20, Folder 4-5)
      - Watch Hill, Rhode Island property-"Intermere" documents, 1898-1949 (Box 20, Folder 6)
        - Architectural renderings and maps, 1898-1923 (Box 21)
      - Yale University Library-gift of manuscript papers of Thomas Day Thacher, 1972-1978 (Box 20, Folder 7)